yo how's it going everybody welcome back
to another gs2 tutorial
so today well i mean this is the third
video i've made today so
today again
let's talk about client flags
and
uh it's triggering server side so
as we've mentioned before there's a
client side and a server side the
clients happening on your system here
and the server side is happening through
the actual server itself so i think it's
important that you know how to access
the server side so that you can actually
implement flags and you know security
measures when programming in general
so flags are used to store data on a
player or even the server so let me open
up my fights real quick slash open flags
as a staff member you can see that
here's a couple flags that i have
already created
um you know they could really hold a lot
of different things like if you're a
staff member this should be client bar
though there's two different there's a
couple different types of flags um the
two we're going to be talking about is
client and client r
so client r can only be changed and
modified and read on server side and
client can be read and changed on your
own client
so it's important that you are using
these appropriately because you don't
want somebody using cheat engine or some
sort of memory manipulation to actually
change these flags in some sort of way
so for the video for the purposes of
this video we're going to be using
client r on the player
so that they they can only access this
flag
by a server side
so we just keep it nice and safe so
let's let's start off by placing an npc
or
um
just a block basically so
um i'm going to be change i'm going to
create a class so that we can actually
use it on these little test dummies
we're going to just be basically
claiming a block
um and we're going to do it server side
so let's create a new class or you can
just script directly in an npc that's up
to you let's just call this
block underscore clay
let's call it block claim okay so now we
have a new class that we can use on all
these so
let's just save this real quick let's
copy
this
and then let's go in here and actually
change these so that it uses that okay
so i'm just going to duplicate it a
couple times
save it okay so now they're all these
are using our new script now
so we already know how to do this let's
call our client side tag here client
side
so let's start off by creating some
client-side stuff so
when it's created
let's
so this is a built-in function uncreated
so basically right when this is rendered
let's just do this dot chat is equal to
unclaimed
so now
we should see oh let me get a semicolon
in here
so now if we update the level you'll see
that they're all unclaimed okay
so now what else do we want to do
we want them to touch it to claim it so
let's do function on
layer
touches
okay
and then
now here's where it gets tricky what
we're going to want to do is trigger
action so now we're going to be
triggering the server side
and for now just put x y
and then here this parameter let's let's
do claim this is really important right
here because this is this is how we're
going to be actually knowing that when
you touch it it's triggering
you know the specific function
so now how do we actually go above the
server side and do this one and trigger
that
so you just create any old function and
it's always going to start like this
it's going to always start on action
and then this next part is
has to be exactly the same
so claim claim
when they touch it it should trigger the
server side
and run this function and this is
completely server-side so that means we
have access to client rnl we can modify
and read it
so when they touch it let's do client r
dot
interacting
w which is to interacting with is equal
to this dot id
so this refers to whatever npc it's on
right and the id is a
built-in game engine id per mpc
so this one might be one two three it's
a good way because no npc will have the
same id when they're created so we'll
know exactly will trigger the server
side
and we'll save to the player who touched
it this id
so now let's see if it worked let's do
let's make the npc this dot
chat it's equal to
um
we'll say
claimed
by
and then we'll concatenate with this
okay
so now let me just update the level
again if we touch one
it says it was claimed by me and this is
server side
so everyone should be able to see this
and we just saved what you just
interacted with so we can
so we can use that so let's open our
flags and check this out
so you'll see
right here i've done some testing before
so let me get rid of that right here
this is what we just created and pumped
into the player
so now we have access to save this flag
and use it in any other script anywhere
anyway so things like graylits things
like money
things like health
something like client art
let's just say health
it's equal to 100 so something like that
but let's get rid of that so now
just like that we have access to
something like this so maybe we just
sleep for
one second
and then we do
this
that chat is
equal to an empty string
let's save that
touch it again
and you see it goes away
let's just do
unclaimed let's just go back to what it
was before
so we claimed it unclaimed claimed
unclaimed
just like that
so you can see how easy it is to
trigger the server side which
is very useful
for securing your data and
you know it's just makes it easier so
you can access this kind of information
elsewhere in other scripts
so you can
fully claim this let's say you don't
want another person to
actually claim it we can set this npc to
be claimed
something like
temp dot claim equals false
and then if they touch it
if it's true
this that chat is
equal to
tamp
let's just copy that
and
copy that
so now it's claimed
and if i got rid of this
maybe if it might be set maybe it needs
to update the level so zero
false
this block is not claimed no one's
touched it
so now when you touch it it's going to
trigger the service side
trigger the server side it was claimed
by me and now it's one so it's claimed
so you can you know further implement
your script to make sure that other
people can't claim it so like let's say
you know it's like a little farming item
or whatever you want it to be
uh you can really think outside the
block so now they're all claimed
and you know that's you know they're
really useful and i'm gonna be going
into depth with other tutorials when i
actually teach you how to do like a
specific thing so to create a specific
weapon to create a specific
staff tool to create a panel text system
um any any sort of that kind of a thing
so
flags are super important make sure
you're using them they're super helpful
to
save data to the player um
perfect so thanks for watching and make
sure to subscribe and watch the rest of
the videos that are on the playlist
because i'm going to continue to be
uploading to
these gs2 tutorials
to hopefully help those who can't really
read the wiki because the wiki is kind
of a mess so you know hopefully these
are helpful and i'm going to keep going
make sure to comment what you want to
see next otherwise i'm just going to
keep going off random things until
you know we get some more comments going
so thanks for watching and
good luck scripting